<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>python on Ravi Wijeratne</title>
    <link>/categories/python/</link>
    <description>Recent content in python on Ravi Wijeratne</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/python/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Science In Practice: Topics Mastery </title>
      <link>/blog/data-science-in-practice-topics-mastery/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/data-science-in-practice-topics-mastery/</guid>
      <description>As I did for COGS 9: Introduction to Data Science in an earlier blogpost, I wanted to quickly take a look at some pre-post survey data from my students in COGS 108 this past Spring.
COGS 108: Data Science In Practice is an upper-level undergraduate data science course. It’s required of cognitive science students but taken by lots of different matjors. Students are expected to have experience programming and the course is intentionally light on exams (read: no exams) and heavy on getting students practice with data science thinking, intuition, and tasks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Achieving Course Objectives in An Intro Programming Course</title>
      <link>/blog/achieving-course-objectives-in-an-intro-programming-course/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/achieving-course-objectives-in-an-intro-programming-course/</guid>
      <description>This post summarizes feedback I received from my awesome students after teaching COGS 18 : Introduction to Python this past Spring quarter at UCSD. While this was my first time teaching the course, it was developed and taught once previously by grad student extraordinaire, Tom Donoghue.
This course is required of all cognitive science majors and is meant to be a true introduction to programming. No prior programming experience is expected or required.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>