<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ravi Wijeratne</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Ravi Wijeratne</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/</guid>
      <description>You can read more about these at the blog Weather Prediction Algorithm In this project I used 50 years of memphis weather data to make a autocorrelation model that could predict the max temperature three days in to the future. The mean absulute error was 8.4
 Random Forest Weather Algorithm This project was similar to the weather prediction algorithm, however, instead of a autocorrelation model this used a random forest algorithm.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Test Post</title>
      <link>/blog/test-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/test-post/</guid>
      <description>This is a test post</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>About Me My name is Ravi Wijeratne. I am a machine learning and python enthusiast. I also enjoy making IOS and android apps. I am 14 years old and live in the Memphis area. I enjoy reading and coding in my spare time.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mushroom Image Classifier iOS App</title>
      <link>/blog/image-classifier-app/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/image-classifier-app/</guid>
      <description>I made a iOS app that can detect if an image has a mushroom in it. I followed Jameson Toole&#39;s tutorial. I built the model in Python using Turi Create. I also used Vision and CoreML to convert it into an app. The project wasn&#39;t too hard and only took a couple of days. The app works pretty well and has a 95.7% accuracy.
Images of the app: </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weather Prediction App</title>
      <link>/blog/weather-prediction-app/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/weather-prediction-app/</guid>
      <description>I have converted my Random Forest Algorithm into an iOS app using CoreML. I followed Brian Advent&#39;s LinkedIn course, iOS App Development: Core ML, to convert my model. I also followed Matt Mathias&amp;rsquo; tutorial. Using both of the courses it was fairly easy to create an app even though I ran into a lot of bugs in Xcode. This was my first programming in Swift and was difficult at first. In the end I was able to make a fully functioning app that predicted the weather in Memphis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Random Forest Weather Prediction Algorithm</title>
      <link>/blog/random-forest/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/random-forest/</guid>
      <description>I created a new random forest weather prediction model using Sklearn. I used William Koehrsen&#39;s tutorial to create the model. The model can predict the maximum temperature in Memphis with a MAE of 4.44 and an accuracy of 92.72%. I got the data from the National Centers for Environmental Information. I had to clean the data, fix some bugs, replace nans, encode the month and day, and get rid of unneeded columns.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weather Prediction Algorithm</title>
      <link>/blog/2018-06-28-weather-prediction/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018-06-28-weather-prediction/</guid>
      <description>I have made a weather prediction algorithm that predicts the maximum temprature in Memphis. I did this by following Brandon Rohrer&#39;s Udemy course End-to-end data science: Time-series prediction. To predict the temprature I used the autocorrelation of one day&#39;s temprature to the next to predict three days into the future. Autocorrelation is when the data at a previous timesteps is useful for predicting at a future timestep. The data had an Autocorrelation of .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Site Launched</title>
      <link>/blog/site-launched/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/site-launched/</guid>
      <description>My site has launched. It’s powered by Jekyll and I can use Markdown to edit my posts.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>